Guide to theGerald Sykes Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Gerald Sykes Papers,
ca. 1921-1984
Sykes, Gerald, 1903-
41 linear ft. (ca.9,150 items in 56 boxes, 155 volumes, & 1 oversize folder).
Columbia University Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Butler Library, New York, NY 10027.
4079758
Biographical Note
Author, editor, critic, and professor of sociology at the New School for Social Research, who died in 1984.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, notes, notebooks, documents, photographs, course-related materials, and printed materials. The manuscripts include typescripts of Sykes' published and unpublished novels, monographs, plays, short stories, and articles. Among these are The Perennial Avant Garde, The Cool Millennium, and The Hidden Remnant. Sykes' notes and notebooks span the period from the early 1930s to 1980, and include preliminary ideas and sketches for his books, as well as autobiographical material. A small number of documents concern Sykes' wartime work in the U.S. Government Office of War Information. Course-related material including writings and correspondence of students taught by Sykes between 1962 and 1975 at the New School and as an adjunct professor at Columbia University. Printed materials consist of numerous reviews of Sykes' books, in addition to offprints and articles by Sykes. Included as well are printed materials about or connected with Sykes, offprints of articles inscribed to him, and many volumes from his library. The substantial correspondence series includes personal letters and correspondence with agents and publishers relating to his books. Correspondents include Harold Clurman, Aaron Copland, Lawrence Durrell, Georgia O'Keeffe, and Francis Steegmuller, as well as a number of Sykes' students. There is extensive correspondence between Sykes and the artist John Hartell from 1927 to 1983.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 11 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Cataloged Photographs
Series III: Arranged Correspondence
Series IV: Arranged Manuscripts
Series V: Notes and Notebooks
Series VI: Appointment and Address Books
Series VII: Documents and Photographs
Series VIII: Ccouse Related Materials
Series IX: Subject Files
Series X: Printed Materials
Series XI: Audio Tapes
Subjects
United States.--Office of War Information.; Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions.; Columbia University.; New School for Social Research (New York, N.Y.); Clurman, Harold, 1901-; Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990.; Diamond, David, 1915-2005.; Durrell, Lawrence.; Fremantle, Anne Jackson, 1909-2002.; Galbraith, John Kenneth, 1908-2006.; Hazzard, Shirley, 1931-; Hicks, Granville, 1901-1982.; Hopkins, Anthony, 1937-; Hutchins, Robert Maynard, 1899-1977.; Isherwood, Christopher, 1904-1986.; Javits, Jacob K. (Jacob Koppel), 1904-1986.; Jung, Karl, 1902-; Kazan, Elia.; Kronenberger, Louis, 1904-1980.; Kunitz, Stanley, 1905-2006.; Lerner, Max, 1902-1992.; MacDowell, Marian, 1857-1956.; McLuhan, Marshall, 1911-1980.; Miller, Henry, 1891-1980.; Miłosz, Czesław.; Moynihan, Daniel P. (Daniel Patrick), 1927-2003.; 0'Keeffe, Georgia, 1887-1986.; Slonimsky, Nicolas, 1894-1995.; Steegmuller, Francis, 1906-1994.; Strand, Hazel.; Strand, Paul, 1890-1976.; Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989.; Trilling, Diana.; Viereck, Peter, 1916-2006.; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975.; American literature--20th century.; Books--Reviews.; Culture.; Drama.; Fiction--Technique.; Interpersonal relations--Study and teaching.; Motion picture plays.; Scenarios.; Social psychology--Study and teaching.; Sociology--Study and teaching.; Television plays.; Address books.; Announcements.; Appointment books.; Articles.; Attendance records.; Card files.; Certificates.; Commonplace books.; Contracts.; Curricula.; Drafts (literary).; Essays.; Examinations.; Fiction.; Galley proofs.; Grade books.; Greeting cards.; Invitations.; Lectures.; Lists.; Manuscripts (literary).; Monographs.; Notebooks.; Notes.; Photographs.; Photoprints.; Poems.; Proofs.; Reprints.; Reviews.; Schedules.; Scripts.; Syllabi.; Art critics.; Authors.; College teachers; Critics.; Dramatists.; Editors.; Novelists, American.; Sociologists.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: 2-57. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1985 M-1985 Papers Sykes, Mrs Gerald Gift
1988 M-1988 Papers Sykes, Mrs Gerald Gift
1991 M-1991 Papers Sykes, Mrs Gerald Gift
09/28/92 M-92-09-28 Papers Sykes, Claire M. Gift
Gift of Mrs Claire Metcalfe Sykes, 1985, 1988, 1991, & 1992.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Clurman, Harold (Box 1)
  - Copeland, Aaron (Box 1)
  - Diamond, David (Box 1)
  - Durrell, Lawrence (Box 1)
  - Fremantle, Anne (Box 1)
  - Galbraith, John Kenneth (Box 1)
  - Hazzard, Shirley (Mrs. Francis Steegmuller) (Box 1)
  - Hicks, Granville (Box 1)
  - Hopkins, Anthony (Box 1)
  - Hutchins, Robert M. (Box 1)
  - Isherwood, Christopher (Box 1)
  - Javits, Jacob (Box 1)
  - Kazan, Elia (Box 1)
  - Kronenberger, Louis (Box 1)
  - Kunitz, Stanley (Box 1)
  - Lerner, Max (Box 1)
  - MacDowell, Marian (Mrs. Edward) (Box 1)
  - McLuhan, Marshall (Box 1)
  - Miller, Henry (Box 1)
  - Milosz, Cselaw (Box 1)
  - Moore, Paul, Jr. (Box 1)
  - Moynihan, Daniel Patrick (Box 1)
  - O'Keefe, Georgia (Box 1)
  - Singer, Isaac B. (Box 1)
  - Slonimskii, Nicholas (Box 1)
  - Steegmuller, Francis (Box 1)
  - Stieglitz, Alfred (Box 1)
  - Strand, Paul & Hazel (Box 1)
  - Thomson, Virgil (Box 1)
  - Trilling, Diana Rubin (Mrs. Lionel) (Box 1)
  - Wilder, Thronton (Box 1)
- Series II: Cataloged Photographs
  - June, Carl (Box 1)
  - Shaw, Alfred Craig (Box 1)
- Series III: Arranged Correspondence
  - A (Box 2)
  - Ali, Ahmed (Box 2)
  - Arpol Travel Agency (Box 2)
  - The Authors' Guild (Box 2)
  - B (Box 2)
  - Barnet, Will (Box 2)
  - Bergman, James R. (Box 2)
  - Britton, Coburg (Box 2)
  - C (Box 2)
  - Camhi, Gail (Box 2)
  - Campbell, Joseph (Box 2)
  - Copland, Aaron (Box 2)
  - Cushman, John (Box 2)
  - D (Box 3)
  - Diamant, Anita (Box 3)
  - Durrell, Lawrence (Box 3)
  - E (Box 3)
  - Edel, Leon (Box 3)
  - Eliade, Mircea (Box 3)
  - Everett, John (Box 3)
  - F & G (Box 3)
  - Galbraith, John Kenneth (Box 3)
  - Greenwald, T. (Box 3)
  - H (Box 4)
  - Harris, Frank (Box 4)
  - Harrison, John (Box 4)
  - Hartell, John (Box 4)
  - Hasentab, Rose (Box 5)
  - Hill, Elena Karam (Box 5)
  - Hivnor, Bob (Box 5)
  - International College (Box 5)
  - J (Box 5)
  - Jacobs, Sandra James (Box 5)
  - Jolles, Paul R. (Box 5)
  - K (Box 6)
  - Kazan, Elia (Box 6)
  - l (Box 6)
  - Lipsey, Roger (Box 6)
  - Luboski, Richard (Box 6)
  - M (Box 6)
  - McLuhan, Marshall (Box 6)
  - Miller, Harvey S. Shipley (Box 6)
  - Motley, Jane (Box 6)
  - N (Box 6)
  - Norton, Dorothy (Box 6)
  - O (Box 7)
  - O'Keefe, Georgia (Box 7)
  - Ong, Walter J., S.J. (Box 7)
  - P (Box 7)
  - Pandelakis, Electra (Box 7)
  - Pownall, Bill & Francesca (Box 7)
  - R (Box 7)
  - Roberts, Roberta (Box 7)
  - Rothschild, Judith (Box 7)
  - S (Box 8)
  - Sheldon, William (Box 8)
  - Singer, Alma (Box 8)
  - Strand, Paul (Box 8)
  - Sykes, Buffie Johnson (Mrs. Gerald I) (Box 8)
  - Sykes, Claire (Mrs. Gerald II) (Box 8)
  - Sykes, Gerald (Box 9)
  - Sykes, Herbert B. (Box 10)
  - Sykes, Jennie (Box 10)
  - Sykes Family (Box 10)
  - T (Box 10)
  - Toffelmier, Gertrude D. (Box 10)
  - U & V (Box 10)
  - Viereck, Peter (Box 10)
  - W (Box 11)
  - Walsh, Chad (Box 11)
  - White, Jon Manchip (Box 11)
  - White, Victor (Box 11)
  - Whittlesey, Marietta (Box 11)
  - Wilkinson, John (Box 11)
  - X, Y, Z (Box 11)
  - Unidentified correspondents (Box 11)
- Series IV: Arranged Manuscripts
  - Foresights [monograph], (1 t.ms.) (Box 12)
  - Foresights, (1 t.ms. (photocopy #1)) (Box 12)
  - Foresights, (1 t.ms. (photocopy #2)) (Box 12)
  - Foresights, (1 t.ms. (photocopy fragment)) (Box 12)
  - Gramercy Brook [novel], (1 t.ms. #1) (Box 13)
  - Gramercy Brook, (1 t.ms. #2) (Box 13)
  - Gramercy Brook, (1 t.ms. #3) (Box 13)
  - Gramercy Brook, (1 t.ms. (extracts)) (Box 13)
  - Gramercy Brook, (1 t.ms. (fragments)) (Box 13)
  - Gramercy Brook, (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 13)
  - Gramercy Brook, (1 t.ms. (photocopy frag. #1)) (Box 13)
  - Gramercy Brook, (1 t.ms. (photocopy frag. #2)) (Box 13)
  - Gramercy Brook, (1 t.ms. (photocopy frag. #3)) (Box 13)
  - The Hidden Remnant [monograph], (1 t.ms. (proofs)) (Box 14)
  - The Hidden Remnant, (1 t.ms. ) (Box 14)
  - The Hidden Remnant, (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 14)
  - The Lust of the Goat [novel] (1), (1 t.ms.) (Box 15)
  - The Lust of the Goat, (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 15)
  - The Lust of the Goat, (1 t.ms. (photocopy fragments)) (Box 15)
  - The Lust of the Goat (2), (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 16)
  - The Most Favored Nation [novel] (1), (1 t.ms.) (Box 17)
  - The Most Favored Nation, (1 t.ms.) (Box 17)
  - The Most Favored Nation, (1 t.ms. (fragment #1)) (Box 17)
  - The Most Favored Nation, (1 t.ms. (fragment #2)) (Box 17)
  - The Most Favored Nation, (1 t.ms. (photocopy #1)) (Box 17)
  - The Most Favored Nation [novel] (2), (1 t.ms. (photocopy #2)) (Box 18)
  - The Most Favored Nation, (1 t.ms. (photocopy fragments #1)) (Box 18)
  - The Most Favored Nation, (1 t.ms. (photocopy fragments #2)) (Box 18)
  - The Most Favored Nation, (1 t.ms. (photocopy fragments #3)) (Box 18)
  - The Most Favored Nation, (1 t.ms. (photocopy fragments #4)) (Box 18)
  - The Most Favored Nation, (1 t.ms. (photocopy fragments #5)) (Box 18)
  - The Perennial Avantgarde [monograph], (1 t.ms.) (Box 19)
  - The Perennial Avantgarde, (1 t.ms. (photocopy, with corrections #1)) (Box 19)
  - The Perennial Avantgarde, (1 t.ms. (photocopy, with corrections #2)) (Box 19)
  - The Perennial Avantgarde, (1 t.ms. (photocopy, with corrections #3)) (Box 19)
  - The Perennial Avantgarde, (1 t.ms. (photocopy, with corrections #4)) (Box 19)
  - The Perennial Avantgarde, (1 t.ms. (photocopy, assorted drafts #1)) (Box 19)
  - The Perennial Avantgarde, (1 t.ms. (photocopy, assorted drafts #2)) (Box 19)
  - The Perennial Avantgarde, (1 t.ms. (assorted drafts for lecture or journal article)) (Box 19)
  - The Shape of Prosperity [novel], (1 t.ms. (photocopy #1)) (Box 20)
  - The Shape of Prosperity, (1 t.ms. (photocopy #2)) (Box 20)
  - The Adults [monograph], (1 t.ms.) (Box 21)
  - The Advance Guard, (1 t.ms. (outline & related materials)) (Box 21)
  - Against the Weather, (1 t.ms. (monograph proposal & related items)) (Box 21)
  - Alienation [monograph], (1 t.ms. (drafts, notes & correspondence)) (Box 21)
  - The Answer [monograph], (1 t.ms. (outline, carbon copy)) (Box 21)
  - Athena [novel], (1 t.ms. (fragment)) (Box 21)
  - Athena [novel], (1 t.ms. (photocopy fragment)) (Box 21)
  - The Battle of New York [novel], (1 t.ms. (notes & related items)) (Box 21)
  - The Battle of New York, (1 t.ms. (carbon copy, early drafts #1)) (Box 21)
  - The Battle of New York, (1 t.ms. (carbon copy, early drafts #2)) (Box 21)
  - The Center of the Stage [novel], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy text for book jacket)) (Box 22)
  - Comparative Copulation [monograph], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 22)
  - The Cool Millennium [monograph], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 22)
  - The Corn Goddess [novel], (1 t.ms. (proposal, with related items)) (Box 23)
  - The Decline of the East [monograph], (1 t.ms. (fragment)) (Box 23)
  - E Pluribus Unum [novel], (1 t.ms. (fragment)) (Box 23)
  - The English Cousin [novel], (1 t.ms. (fragment)) (Box 23)
  - The Forbidden Tree [monograph], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy, fragment)) (Box 24)
  - The Forbidden Tree, (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 24)
  - The Forest of New York [novel], (1 t.ms. ) (Box 24)
  - The Golden Touch [novel], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 24)
  - Zlissos [novel], (1 t.ms.) (Box 25)
  - The Manufacturer to Christ [novel], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 25)
  - The Men's Tradegy [novel], (1 t.ms.) (Box 25)
  - The Men's Tradegy, (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 25)
  - The Midas Touch [novel], (1 t.ms.) (Box 25)
  - The Midas Touch, (1 t.ms. (photocopy fragments)) (Box 25)
  - The Modern Ark [novel], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 26)
  - The Navel of the World [novel], (1 t.ms. ) (Box 26)
  - The New Inferno [novel], (1 t.ms. (photocopy fragments)) (Box 26)
  - The Nice American [novel], (1 t.ms. (proposal)) (Box 27)
  - The Nice American, (1 t.ms. (miscellaneous notes)) (Box 27)
  - Our New Elite [monograph], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 27)
  - Peace by Parachute [monograph], (1 t.ms. (proposal, notes, realted items)) (Box 27)
  - The Price of Technology [monograph], (1 t.ms. (fragments & related items)) (Box 27)
  - The Redskin Farce [novel], (1 t.ms.) (Box 27)
  - The Redskin Farce, (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 27)
  - The Rules of the Game [novel], (1 t.ms. (fragment)) (Box 27)
  - The Rules of the Game, (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 27)
  - The Rules of the Game, (1 t.ms. (carbon copy fragment)) (Box 27)
  - Scotus & Alexander [novel], (1 t.ms.) (Box 27)
  - The Serenity Game [novel], (1 t.ms.) (Box 27)
  - The Serenity Trend [novel], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 28)
  - Still Champion [monograph], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 28)
  - Still Champion, (1 t.ms. (photocopy fragments)) (Box 28)
  - Tinto's Malley [novel], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 28)
  - Touch Wood [novel], (1 t.ms. (photocopy fragments)) (Box 28)
  - The Transformation of the Mind [monograph], (1 t.ms. (photocopy fragment)) (Box 29)
  - Tree [novel], (1 t.ms.) (Box 29)
  - Tumbleweed [monograph], (1 t.ms.) (Box 29)
  - Tumbleweed, (1 t.ms. (photocopy & related items)) (Box 29)
  - Two Against Thebes [novel], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 29)
  - Unidentified work [monograph], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy of foreward)) (Box 29)
  - Unidentified work [novel], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 29)
  - Unidentified work [novel], (1 t.ms. (chapter 1, fragment)) (Box 29)
  - Unidentified work [novel], (1 t.ms. & a.ms. notes) (Box 29)
  - Unidentified work [novel], (1 t.ms. (incomplete)) (Box 29)
  - Unidentified work [monograph], (1 t.ms. (index)) (Box 29)
  - Unidentified work [novel], (1 t.ms. (miscellaneous notes & draft pages)) (Box 29)
  - Abe Lincoln [script], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 30)
  - Ancient History [play], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 30)
  - The Animal Collective [play], (1 t.ms.) (Box 30)
  - Bicentennial [play], (1 t.ms. (photocopy #1)) (Box 30)
  - Bicentennial, (1 t.ms. (photocopy #2)) (Box 30)
  - Bicentennial, (1 t.ms. (photocopy #3)) (Box 30)
  - The Bigger Rev. [play], (1 t.ms. (photocopy #1)) (Box 30)
  - The Bigger Rev., (1 t.ms. (photocopy #2)) (Box 30)
  - The Bigger Rev., (1 t.ms. (photocopy #3)) (Box 30)
  - Blind Spots [script], (1 t.ms. (photocopy proposal with related correspondence)) (Box 30)
  - The Cosy Chaos [script], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 30)
  - Cowboys and Indians [play], (1 t.ms. ) (Box 30)
  - Cowboys and Indians, (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 30)
  - The Eye of the Pyramid [play], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 30)
  - Faust in Ohio [play], (1 t.ms. ) (Box 30)
  - Grand Larceny, Unlimited [play], (1 t.ms. ) (Box 30)
  - The Lust of the Goat [play], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 31)
  - The Navel of the World [play], (1 t.ms. (photocopy #1)) (Box 31)
  - The Navel of the World, (1 t.ms. (photocopy #2)) (Box 31)
  - The Nice American [play], (1 t.ms. (photocopy #1)) (Box 31)
  - The Nice American, (1 t.ms. (photocopy #2)) (Box 31)
  - The Nice American, (1 t.ms. (photocopy #3)) (Box 31)
  - The Nice American, (1 t.ms. (miscellaneous notes)) (Box 31)
  - The One Green Thing [play], (1 t.ms. (photocopy #1)) (Box 32)
  - The One Green Thing, (1 t.ms. (photocopy #2)) (Box 32)
  - The One Green Thing, (1 t.ms. (photocopy #3)) (Box 32)
  - The One Green Thing, (1 t.ms. (photocopy #4)) (Box 32)
  - Papa PR [play], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 32)
  - Pussywillow [play], (1 t.ms. ) (Box 32)
  - Pygmalia [play], (1 t.ms. (fragment)) (Box 32)
  - The Recovery of the Sacred [script], (1 t.ms.) (Box 32)
  - The Savage [script], (1 t.ms.) (Box 32)
  - The Scapegoat Farce [play], (1 t.ms.) (Box 32)
  - The Serenity Gene [play], (1 t.ms.) (Box 32)
  - Such Men Are Dangerous [play], (1 t.ms.) (Box 32)
  - Touch Wood [script], (1 t.ms.) (Box 33)
  - Touch Wood, (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 33)
  - The Trojan Farce [script], (1 t.ms.) (Box 33)
  - White Hope [play], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 33)
  - Untitled [play], (1 t.ms. #1) (Box 33)
  - Untitled, (1 t.ms. #2) (Box 33)
  - Albert Pinkham [article], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 34)
  - The American Three [article], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 34)
  - Anite de Caro [article], (1 t.ms. ) (Box 34)
  - Apology for My Health [short story], (1 t.ms. #1) (Box 34)
  - Apology for My Health, (1 t.ms. #2) (Box 34)
  - Apology for My Health, (1 t.ms. (carbon copy #1)) (Box 34)
  - Apology for My Health, (1 t.ms. (carbon copy #2)) (Box 34)
  - The Archetypes of Everyday Life [article], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 34)
  - At First Sight [short story], (1 t.ms.) (Box 34)
  - Autobiographical information, (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 34)
  - Ballad of the Nasty Lawyer Man [article], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 34)
  - Ballad of the Nasty Lawyer Man [article], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 34)
  - The Birth of a New Heroine [article], (1 t.ms.) (Box 34)
  - The Birth of a New Heroine, (1 t.ms. (photocopy & related correspondence)) (Box 34)
  - The Biting Horse [article], (1 t.ms.) (Box 34)
  - The Biting Horse, (2 t.ms. (carbon copies)) (Box 34)
  - Cedo Senioribus [essay], (2 t.ms.) (Box 34)
  - A Change of Government [short story], (1 t.ms.) (Box 34)
  - A Change of Government, (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 34)
  - Choice and Transformation [review article], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 34)
  - A Classroom Feud [short story], (1 t.ms.) (Box 34)
  - Confidential From the President [short story], (1 t.ms.) (Box 34)
  - Consciousness [article], (1 t.ms. (with a.ms. notes)) (Box 34)
  - The Coroner's Report on American Literature [article], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 34)
  - The Devil's Advocate Speaks [article], (1 t.ms. (with related material)) (Box 34)
  - Disavowal [poem], (2 t.ms.) (Box 34)
  - Do Women Rule America? [article], (1 t.ms.) (Box 34)
  - Down to Earth [short story], (1 t.ms.) (Box 34)
  - The Earl of Whoam [short story], (2 t.ms.) (Box 34)
  - The Earl of Whoam, (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 34)
  - Europe's Obsession [article], (1 t.ms.) (Box 34)
  - The Face of a Star [short story], (1 t.ms. (fragments & carbon copy)) (Box 34)
  - Family Skeleton [short story], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 34)
  - Fantasy in Cold Print [article], (1 t.ms.) (Box 34)
  - The First Affait [ short story], (1 t.ms.) (Box 34)
  - The First Kiss in Four Years [short story], (1 t.ms.) (Box 34)
  - The First Kiss in Four Years, (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 34)
  - The First Step in Discovering a New World [lecture], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 34)
  - First Surmise [short story], (1 t.ms.) (Box 34)
  - First Surmise, (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 34)
  - The Fish [article], (1 t.ms.) (Box 34)
  - Folksong [short story], (1 t.ms. (fragment)) (Box 34)
  - Frederick Sykes [srticle], (2 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 34)
  - The Friend of Labor [short story], (1 t.ms. ) (Box 34)
  - The Funeral of Beautiful Letters [article], (1 t.ms. (with photocopy)) (Box 34)
  - The Funeral of Beautiful Letters, (1 t.ms. (notes & related items)) (Box 34)
  - Geld Your Enemy [short story], (1 t.ms.) (Box 34)
  - Gogol and His Children [article], (1 t.ms.) (Box 34)
  - Good-Looking Men [short story], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 34)
  - Greatness Here and Now [short story], (1 t.ms. (fragment)) (Box 34)
  - Her Preference [short story], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 34)
  - An Invalid's Burial [short story], (1 t.ms. #1) (Box 34)
  - An Invalid's Burial, (1 t.ms. #2) (Box 34)
  - Isherwood's Review [review article], (1 t.ms.) (Box 34)
  - Judge Bouvier [article], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 34)
  - Jung Article [article], (1 t.ms. (with related correspondence)) (Box 34)
  - Jung Article, (1 t.ms. (carbon copy & related materials)) (Box 34)
  - The Kid Nextdoor [short story], (1 t.ms.) (Box 35)
  - The Lady or the Princeton [short story], (2 t.ms.) (Box 35)
  - A Letter from Paris [article], (1 tms. (carbon copies various drafts)) (Box 35)
  - A Letter from Salzburg [article], (1 t.ms.) (Box 35)
  - A Letter from Yugoslavia [article], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 35)
  - Literature and Science [article], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 35)
  - The Literature of the Remnant [article], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 35)
  - [Mann], Thomas [article], (1 t.ms.) (Box 35)
  - The Mental Requirements for Modern Power [article], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 35)
  - A Mighty Fortress [short story], (1 t.ms.) (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous notes & sketches, (1 t.ms.) (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous Reviews [1], (1 t.ms.) (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous Reviews [2], (1 t.ms.) (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous Reviews [3], (1 t.ms.) (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous Reviews [4], (1 t.ms.) (Box 35)
  - New York as Axis Mundi, (2 t.ms.) (Box 35)
  - Nicolai Gogol [article], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 35)
  - A Note on My Chief Source of Information [article], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 35)
  - The Novelist as Foreign Correspondent [article], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 35)
  - On Keeping the Purity of a Pirate’s Nook [article], (1 t.ms. (with photocopy)) (Box 35)
  - One Vote for the Sun [article], (1 t.ms.) (Box 35)
  - One Vote for the Sun, (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 35)
  - Only Over There [short story], (1 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 35)
  - Paintings by Buffie Johnson [article], (1 t.ms. (various drafts & related materials)) (Box 35)
  - The Paintings of Nina Jacobson [article], (1 t.ms.) (Box 35)
  - Paintings of Will Barnet [article], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy and related items)) (Box 35)
  - Phaedrus No More [short story], (1 t.ms.) (Box 35)
  - Pleasures Formerly Unexplored [article], (1 t.ms. (with related correspondence)) (Box 35)
  - Portrait of a Player [short story], (1 t.ms.) (Box 35)
  - The Post-Electron Poet [article], (3 t.ms. (drafts with differing titles)) (Box 35)
  - Present-Day Modes of Escapism [article], (1 t.ms. (photocopy with German translation)) (Box 35)
  - A Psychology for Americans [article], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 35)
  - Return to Childhood [short story], (1 t.ms.) (Box 36)
  - The Sand Fortress [short story], (1 t.ms.) (Box 36)
  - Science and Culture [article], (2 t.ms.) (Box 36)
  - A Science in the Making [article], (3 t.ms.) (Box 36)
  - The Search for a Sustaining Myth [article], (2 t.ms. (photocopy)) (Box 36)
  - The Serenity Trend [short story], (1 t.ms.) (Box 36)
  - Shamanism [review], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 36)
  - The Sky Is Blue [review article], (1 t.ms.) (Box 36)
  - Sparrowgrass [short story], (2 t.ms.) (Box 36)
  - Special to the Times [article], (1 t.ms.) (Box 36)
  - Strand Portrait of Alfred Steiglitz, (1 t.ms. (with related materials)) (Box 36)
  - Technology & Politics [article], (1 t.ms.) (Box 36)
  - The Third Culture, (2 t.ms.) (Box 36)
  - To an Unborn Halfbreed [article], (1 t.ms.) (Box 36)
  - The Toiletmaker’s Hurry [article], (1 t.ms.) (Box 36)
  - Touring India at a Distance [article], (1 t.ms.) (Box 36)
  - The Travelling American Painter [article], (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 36)
  - A Trophy for Your Zoo [short story], (1 t.ms.) (Box 36)
  - Trying to Meet My Uncle [short story], (1 t.ms. # 1) (Box 36)
  - Trying to Meet My Uncle, (1 t.ms. #2) (Box 36)
  - Trying to Meet My Uncle, (1 t.ms. (carbon copy)) (Box 36)
  - Two Learned Disputes About Women [article], (1 t.ms. (with carbon copy)) (Box 36)
  - Two Rivers [article], (1 t.ms. (with related items)) (Box 36)
  - The Unseen [short story], (1 t.ms. (fragment)) (Box 36)
  - Waking Up in Fez [article], (3 t.ms.) (Box 36)